computing.net 2016-12-06

# Privacy Policy | Purch

Purch has created this Privacy Policy in order to set forth the principles governing our information-gathering and dissemination practices, including but not limited to such activities as forums, chat rooms, personal profile pages, product reviews, article commentary, blogs, RSS feeds and newsletters, among other offerings. Purch has a strong commitment to the privacy of our users. Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through Purch and not to information collected offline or to information you may provide to any third-party sites to which Purch may link, except as expressly provided herein.

**Purch has updated its privacy policy to clarify how it collects, uses, stores and shares data and to provide more details around these practices. Please read this Privacy Policy as you consent to these data practices by using this Website.**

Your privacy is very important to us. This Privacy Policy describes and governs the information collection, use, and sharing practices of Purch Group, Inc. and its corporate affiliates (collectively, “Purch,” “we,” “us,” and “our”) with respect to Purch’s websites and interactive services that link to this Privacy Policy from the Privacy Policy link included on such sites and services (together, the “Websites”).

Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by Purch and not to information collected by any third-party sites to which Purch may link or information provided to or collected by third-parties through third-party cookies, web beacons, and other third-party technologies served during your visit to the Websites.

**Effective Date**

October 6, 2015

**Information We Collect and How We Collect It**

**Personal Information**

We collect both personal and non-personal information. For the purpose of this policy, when we use the term “Personal Information” we mean information that is collected in conjunction with a name and which would allow someone to identify you or contact you. This may include a first and last name and:

-an email address  
-home address  
-business address  
-phone number  
-username and password associated with your account  
-or other such information about you that you provide directly to us through the Websites

We may collect Personal Information from you when you register to use a particular feature of one of our Websites, when you register to participate in a community forum, when you sign up to receive email newsletters, when you request a price quote from one of our vendors, when you purchase a product or service from one of our Websites, when you use a third party website or services, or in other instances where you affirmatively provide such information to us. In addition, if you order a product or service that we offer for sale on one of our Websites, in addition to your name and contact information, we will also collect and may maintain your billing address, shipping address, product selections, your order number and information about your computer’s internet address and website which may have referred or directed you to the Site (e.g., the referring URL).

We do not currently collect financial information, such as your payment method (valid credit card number, type, expiration date or other financial information); that information is collected and stored by our third party payment processing company (the “Payment Processor”), and use and storage of that information is governed by the Payment Processor’s applicable terms of service and privacy policy.

**Collected Information**  
When we use the term “Collected Information” we mean information other than Personal Information that we (either directly or through our service providers) collect whenever you visit the Websites or otherwise interact with us online.

For example, when you visit a Website, our systems, or those of our service providers, may automatically recognize your domain name and IP address(es), date and time of visits, the type of browser you use, the website from which your visit originated, page visits, time spent on web pages, the subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over and other data that we collect automatically or otherwise as a matter of course.

Technology is always changing, but we generally acquire Collected Information in the following ways:

**IP Address.** Your IP Address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer by your Internet service provider whenever you are on the Internet. When you view pages from any of our Websites, our servers may record or “log” your IP Address and sometimes your domain name.

**Cookies.** Cookies are text files created by a website and stored on your computer. Cookies may be set to store information during a visit or for a longer period of time. Our Websites use cookies to customize your experience. Cookies may also track where you travel on any of our Websites, what advertisements and content you look at, and where you go after you leave one of our Websites.

**Clear GIFs.** A Clear GIF (also sometimes called a “web beacon”) is typically a one-pixel, transparent image (although it can be a visible image as well), located on a web page or in an e-mail or other type of message, which is retrieved from a remote website on the Internet enabling the verification of an individual’s viewing or receipt of a web page or message. We use Clear GIFs in much the same way as cookies.

**Your “Clicks”.** Our server also may record the page that linked you to us and related information such as any ads you may have clicked.

**Device IDs.** You may be visiting one of our Websites from your mobile device such as a mobile phone or tablet. Certain mobile service providers uniquely identify mobile devices. We or our third-party service providers may receive such information if you access our Websites through mobile devices. Some of our technology partners also may assign Device ID numbers to personal computers or other devices. Some features of the Websites may allow for the collection of mobile phone numbers. We may associate that phone number to mobile device identification information. Furthermore, some mobile device providers operate systems that pinpoint the physical location of devices that use their service. Depending on the provider, we or our third-party service providers may receive this information as well. For more information on our treatment of physical location information, please see the section “Geolocation” below.

**Other Websites.** We may use certain technologies, such as tracking pixels, to see websites you visit after you visit our Websites.

**Email.** If you receive email from us, we may use certain tools to capture data such as when you open our message or click on any links or banners our email contains. Some email messages may also contain tracking pixels or other technologies that collect and provide data to us.

**Future Technologies**. Technology is always changing. We are constantly working with our technology partners to find and experiment with new ways to better understand how we can provide an optimal experience for our users and better execute our business strategy.

The technologies listed above and other similar technologies that are used by us to collect Collected Information are referred to herein as “Tracking Technologies”. This Privacy Policy covers our use of Tracking Technologies only, and does not cover the use of Tracking Technologies by third parties. We do not control when or how third parties place Tracking Technologies on your computer. For example, third party websites to which a link points may set Tracking Technologies on your computer.

In some cases, we may link the Collected Information we receive through the Tracking Technologies with some of your Personal Information. You may set your web browser software to reject certain Tracking Technologies. If you do so, certain functionality of the Website that you are visiting may be affected.

**Geolocation**  
If you use the PurchX application on a mobile phone or other mobile device, we may collect general information regarding your physical location. If you visit the Websites from a personal computer or laptop, we may also collect general information regarding your physical location.

**Facebook Connect; Social Media Share Links**  
Some of our Websites allow you to sign up and log in using your Facebook account. If you sign up using Facebook, Facebook will ask your permission to share certain information from your Facebook account with Purch. This includes your first name, last name, gender, general location, a link to your Facebook profile, your timezone, birthday, profile picture, your “likes” and your list of friends.

This information is collected by Facebook and is provided to us under the terms of Facebook’s privacy policy (<http://www.facebook.com/policy.php>). You can control the information that we receive from Facebook using the privacy settings in your Facebook account.

If you signed up using Facebook by mistake, you can delete your account from the Account page within your Settings at any time, or you can email us at privacy@purch.com.

When you “like” or “follow” us on Facebook, Instagram, Pinterest, Twitter or other social media sites, we may collect your information. This information may include your name, e-mail address, and any comments or content you post relevant to us. We may also collect your information if you sign up for one of our promotions or submit information to us through Facebook, Pinterest, Instagram, Twitter or another social media site.

Our Websites may also contain links to other websites, such as Facebook, Twitter, or Pinterest, that are not under our control. These links may include the use of so-called “share links.” A “share link” is a button and/or text link appearing on our Websites that launches a sharing mechanism that allows you to post links to, and content from, our Websites or application onto other websites.

Remember that if you submit information through social media sites, your information is also governed by their privacy policies, and the information you share might be seen by the general public.

**Combining Information**  
We may combine your Personal Information with Collected Information. We may also obtain information about you from our business partners or other outside sources and combine it with your Personal Information and Collected Information. For example, we may purchase demographic and other marketing information from third-parties to help us better serve you or to inform you about services that may be of interest to you. We may also purchase lists containing your Personal Information ( _e.g._ , postal address, phone number, email address) for advertising and marketing purposes.

**How We Use Personal Information and Collected Information**

We use your Personal Information and Collected Information:

-to provide services to you,  
-to process a transaction when your purchase a product or service from one of our Websites,  
-for administrative purposes,  
-to improve our services,  
-to customize the advertising and content you see,  
-to contact you, and  
-for internal business purposes.

We may also use your email address to send you news and information about our company and products that might be of interest to you. You can opt-out of receiving future communications from us about special offers and new product information. You can unsubscribe by following instructions contained in the messages you receive. You can also change your preferences for marketing or disclosure to third parties by clicking on the “Manage My Profile” or “My Account” link on the top of certain Websites. If you are accessing a Website via a mobile device, you can manage your information by touching the “settings” icon. Even if you opt-out of receiving these messages, we reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to the services we provide. We may also send you service announcements and administrative messages. We do not offer you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving those communications.

We may also use anonymous information, such as information pertaining to web or mobile pages you have viewed, in order to analyze trends, track user’s movements, provide a better user experience and gather demographic information for aggregate use.

Please see the section titled, “Behavioral Advertising” to learn how to make choices regarding how we use Collected Information in connection with the delivery of advertising to you. As stated above, we do not currently collect financial information, as that information is collected and stored by our Payment Processor. However, we may from time to time request and receive some of your financial information from our Payment Processor for the purposes of completing transactions you have initiated through the Services, enrolling you in discount, rebate, and other programs in which you elect to participate, protecting against or identifying possible fraudulent transactions, and otherwise as needed to manage our business.

**How We Share the Information We Collect**

**Our Service Providers**  
We may share your Personal Information or Collected Information with third-parties that perform services for us. Third-party service providers may, among other things:

-help us to provide services that you request,  
-to prepare and distribute communications, or  
-to respond to inquiries.

We may also share your Personal Information or Collected Information with certain third-party service providers to:

-operate the Websites,  
-provide general statistics regarding the use of the Websites,  
-analyze and develop our business strategy,  
-determine how you found out about us,  
-determine your interests regarding our products and services,  
-help improve our Websites,  
-create marketing programs for you and others, and  
-for other purposes.

**Merchant Affiliates**  
If you request a price quote or complete a questionnaire regarding a product or service that interests you, you agree that we may share your Personal Information and other information that you submit in the quote request or questionnaire with BuyerZone.com (a site operated by a subsidiary of Purch). BuyerZone.com will use the information and may share it with vendors offering the product or service you want to buy. BuyerZone.com has its own privacy policy that covers this sharing of information; you can find that policy at <http://www.buyerzone.com/about-us/privacy/>.

**Surveys**  
Occasionally, we conduct user surveys to better understand the needs of our audience in order to improve our features. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our advertisers and partners. We never share any survey information about specific individuals with any third party without the user’s consent.

**Law Enforcement and Legal Process**  
We may report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we believe to be unlawful. We may also report any activities that we believe may aid a law enforcement investigation into unlawful activity. We also reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information as we reasonably believe is necessary, in our sole judgement, to (i) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, (ii) enforce this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations hereof, (iii) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, (iv) respond to user support requests, or (v) protect the rights, property or safety, of Purch, the public, or another user. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and spam/malware prevention.

**Sharing Your Information as Permitted By Law**  
We may share your information with others as required by law. We may also share your information with others as permitted by law. This may include sharing your information with government entities or third-parties in response to subpoenas, court orders, other legal process. We may also share your information if we believe it is necessary to exercise our legal rights, to defend against legal claims that have been brought against us, or to defend against possible legal claims that we determine might be brought against us.

**Business Transition**  
As we continue to develop our business, we may buy, merge or partner with other companies. If that happens, we may acquire customer information. In such transactions, user information may be among the transferred assets. Similarly, if a portion or all of Purch’s assets are sold or transferred to a third-party, customer information (including your email address) would likely be one of the transferred business assets.

**Behavioral Advertising**  
We may use third-parties (such as network advertisers) to serve advertisements on our Websites, and we may use traffic measurement services to analyze traffic on our Websites. Network advertisers are third-parties that display advertisements based on your visits to our Websites and other websites you have visited. This practice is sometimes called “behavioral advertising.”

Third-party ad serving allows us and third-parties to target advertisements to you for products and services that may interest you (behavioral advertising). Our Websites’ third-party ad network providers, the advertisers, the sponsors, and/or traffic measurement services may set and access their own cookies and other Tracking Technologies on your computer. For example, the Google Trusted Store badge displayed on some of our Websites is served to you through the use of cookies. Cookies may also track certain behavioral information regarding users of your computer via a Device ID. These third-party cookies and other Tracking Technologies are set to, among other things:

-help deliver advertisements to you for products or services that may be of interest to you,  
-prevent you from seeing the same advertisements too many times, and  
-help us and the third parties understand the usefulness to you of the advertisements that have been delivered to you.

Any images (or any other parts of a web page) served by third-parties in association with third-party cookies may serve as web beacons which enable third-parties to carry out the previously described activities.

Third-party cookies, web beacons, and other third-party Tracking Technologies are governed by each third-party’s specific privacy policy, not this one.

We use a variety of companies to serve advertisements on our Websites.

You may wish to visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/> (the “NAI Site”) and<http://www.aboutads.info/principles/>  (the “DAA Site”) to learn more about online advertising including behavioral advertising. The NAI Site provides information about the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”), its members, and your choices regarding having information used by NAI companies, including the “opt-out” procedures of NAI members which are located at: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>.  The DAA Site provides information about the Digital Advertising Alliance and the companies who participate in its transparency and choice program around interest-based advertising.  You can opt-out of having the participating companies collect Web viewing data for interest- based advertising by visiting this page: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.

You may also wish to visit Google’s advertising opt-out page located at: <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/>. There you will find information about “opting-out” of Google’s use of cookies to serve ads based on your prior visits to our Websites.

Please note that if you delete, block, or otherwise restrict cookies, or if you use a different computer or Internet browser, you will need to renew your opt-out choice. Also, if you choose to opt out of having your information used to deliver advertisements tailored to your interests, you will continue to see advertisements on this website, but these advertisements may not be as relevant to you.

For additional information on cookies and web beacons, please visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>.

**How We Secure Personal Information**

We take reasonable and appropriate measures to help keep information secure and to help prevent it from becoming disclosed to individuals who are not described in this policy. Even though we follow reasonable procedures to try to protect the information in our possession, no security system is perfect, and we cannot promise, and you should not expect, that your information will be secure in all circumstances. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time.

Your account information will be protected by a password for your privacy and security, but we also recommend that you change your password periodically. You are responsible for maintaining the security of your account username and password. You may not provide these account credentials to any third party. If you believe that your account username and/or password have been stolen or been made known to others, you must contact us immediately at **privacy@purch.com** and change your password immediately via the Websites. We are not responsible if someone else accesses your Account through information that they have obtained from you.

**How We Communicate With You**

If you have any questions about our privacy policy, you can contact us by emailing us at **privacy@purch.com**. If we need, or are required, to contact you concerning any event that involves your information, we may do so by email, telephone, or mail.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

Residents of the State of California, under certain provisions of the California Civil Code, have the right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third-parties to which the company has disclosed certain personally identifiable information as defined under California law during the preceding year for third-party direct marketing purposes.

You are limited to one request per calendar year. In your request, please attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for our response. You may request the information in writing at:

Privacy  
Purch  
150 Fifth Avenue, 9th Floor  
New York, New York 10011

**Miscellaneous**

**Do Not Track Signals**  
Some web browsers and devices allow you to broadcast a preference that your activities online not be “tracked”. At this time, the Websites do not take action in response to “do not track” signals.

**Children**  
We do not provide products and services to children. We do not knowingly collect or solicit information from children under the age of 13.

If you are a parent or guardian of a child under the age of thirteen (13) and believe he or she has disclosed personally identifiable information to us, please contact us at **privacy@purch.com**.

A parent or guardian of a child under the age of thirteen (13) may review and request deletion of a child’s personally identifiable information as well as prohibit the use thereof. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we take steps to remove that information and terminate the child’s account.

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**  
We reserve the right to modify or amend this policy at any time by posting the revised privacy policy on our Websites. If we make changes in the way we collect or use information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on the Websites, or contacting you by email, telephone, or mail. Material changes will only affect the information we collect after the effective date of the change to our privacy policy unless we clearly express otherwise.

**Changing and Deleting**  
You may access your personal information through your profiles on our Websites and delete, change, or modify that information by clicking on the “Manage My Profile” or “My Account” link on the top of certain Websites. If you are accessing a Website via a mobile device, you can manage your information by touching the “settings” icon. For additional assistance with modifying or deleting information provided to our Websites, contact us at **privacy@purch.com.**

If you terminate your account, any association between your account and information we store will no longer be accessible through your account. However, given the nature of sharing on the Websites, any public activity on your account prior to deletion will remain stored on our servers and will remain accessible to the public.

**Public Forums**  
Our Websites offer publicly accessible blogs and community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blogs or community forums, please contact us. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

Please also remember that if you choose to provide Personal Information using certain public features of the Websites, then that information is governed by the privacy settings of those particular features and may be publicly available. Individuals reading such information may use or disclose it to other individuals or entities without our control and without your knowledge, and search engines may index that information. We therefore urge you to think carefully about what you choose to disclose publicly and make sure it’s information you want to share with everyone.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement or any other issue with our Websites, you may contact us at: **privacy@purch.com**.
